# RAMESH YOHA (RAMESHKANNA YOHALINGAM)

http://www.yramesh.dev https://www.gitlab.com/ramesh.yoha SCARBOROUGH, ON, M1S 5B2 416.684.7983 • ramesh.yohalingam@gmail.com

Technically sophisticated engineering professional with extensive experience in full stack application development and database management. Highly skilled in web application development, database management systems, user interface designs, and web design. Effective communicator with aptitude for building relationships that support organizational goals.

#### **AREAS OF EXPERTISE:**

- Designing & Developing Web Applications
- Database Management & Reporting
- Project Management
- Systems Implementation
- Support, Fix & Update Applications

- Testing & Debugging
- Programming & Scripting
- Client Relationship Management
- Troubleshooting & Problem Resolution
- User Training and Support

#### TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

PROGRAMMING Java(13), J2EE, Spring Boot, Kotlin, Python, React.JS, Node.JS, Angular.JS,

**LANGUAGES:** Shell/Bash

DATABASE MS SQL, Oracle, NoSQL, Redis Caching, DataGrid, SQL Server 2008/2012,
MANAGEMENT: Crystal Reports, CouchBase, Mongo, Sybase, Tableu, Adobe Campaign

TESTING: Postman, SOAP UI, JMeter, JUnit, Jest, Mocha, Sonarqube, Fortify, Detekt

**OPERATIONS/CLOUD:** Weblogic, TomCat, Jenkins, Maven, Gradle, Docker, Openshift(Paas), GCP, AWS,

PCF, Azure, Git/TFS, Apache Nifi , Kafka, Pub/Sub

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE -

PAYMENTUS, Richmond Hill, ON, Canada

#### SENIOR FULL-STACK ENGINEER

JANUARY 2020 - PRESENT

- 1. Developed payment platform front end applications based on the specific client requirements using FTL
- 2. Modified liability micro service on node.js to fetch and post user data to AWS
- 3. Identified and fixed the production bugs raised by the clients on both front-end and back-end
- 4. Developed Report generators on successful posted payments and refunded payments
- 5. Developed email templates specific to the client for each payment transaction
- 6. Contributed suggestions/comments on peer reviews and demos for better coding practice

**Technologies:** Java/J2EE(13), Spring, Node.JS, Apache FTL, Shell/Bash, Oracle, Tomcat, AWS, Postman, Junit(5), Jest, Mocha, Maven, Git/BitBucket, Jenkins, Kibana, DKron

SCOTIABANK, Scarborough, ON, Canada

#### **SENIOR JAVA DEVELOPER**

March 2019 - January 2020

- 1. Developed complete multi factor authentication system using Spring Boot as the backend
- 2. Authentication system supports sign in, reset password, change password, reset username, enroll profile, enroll bio-metrics, authenticate high risk transactions, one-time-password authentications
- 3. Designed and developed DB tables to store authentication details
- 4. Developed database stored procedure (Sybase) scripts to support CRUD activities
- 5. Developed push notification services to authenticate users logging in via web application using azure notification hub, APNS (apple), firebase (android)
- 6. Two factor authentication contains bio-metrics sign in using POK signature verification
- 7. Developed Redis Server sessions to handle multiple requests per session
- 8. Designed & Developed RESTful web services to support the authentication workflow, by gathering business requirements
- 9. Handled Alerts via Email and Push notifications for each high-risk transaction
- 10. Developed Credential Provisioning API using Kotlin and Spring Boot

**Technologies:** Java/J2EE (8), Spring Boot, Node.JS, Kotlin, Shell/Bash, Sybase, Tomcat, PCF/Azure, Postman, JMeter, Junit, Jacaco, Sonarqube, Fortify, Gradle, Git/BitBucket, Redis Cache, Detekt

## RAMESH YOHA

### TELUS COMMUNICATIONS INC, Scarborough, ON, Canada

#### **DEVELOPER ANALYST (III)**

JUNE 2018 - MARCH 2019

- 1. Developed multiple Spring Boot RESTFul Web services to perform Communication related CRUD
- 2. Developed RESTFul Web service subscribed to Apache Kafka queue which writes to Oracle Coherence Datagrid
- 3. Developed scripts to enhance existing eventing system to record and restore the missing events while downtime/failure
- 4. Developed scripts to Integrated Telus applications with Sonarqube for code quality
- 5. Worked on Code Quality Tableu Dashboard to visualize the Sonarqube data for each team
- 6. Fixed the code smells (blockers and criticals) identified by Sonarqube on the existing applications
- 7. Developed event listener to push events to Google Cloud Pub Sub
- 8. Created templates on Adobe Campaign for marketing emails and sms
- 9. Worked on GCP App Engine and google mail API to receive emails and store in Cloud storage (Similar to AWS SES & S3)
- 10. Developed test suites on postman for regression and sanity testing
- 11. Developed Web service to retrieve saved email from GCP Storage with signed URL
- 12. Developed Notification viewer dashboard using React JS and Node JS
- 13. Designed multiple relational database tables to store Notification details

**Technologies:** Java/J2EE(8), Spring Boot, Node.JS, React.JS, Oracle, Adobe Campaign, Postman, SOAP UI, Junit, Katalon, Tomcat, Jenkins, Maven, Docker, Openshift(Paas), GCP/AWS, Git, Apache Nifi, CouchBase(NoSQL), Slack, Agile, Sonarqube, Linux(Ubuntu), Windows 2000 Server

# **TELUS COMMUNICATIONS INC,** Scarborough, ON, Canada **DEVELOPER ANALYST (II)**

**SEPTEMBER 2016 - JUNE 2018** 

- 1. Design & Development with J2EE, Spring framework and Oracle Coherence Data Grid architecture application
- 2. Developed SOAP and RESTful web services on Spring Framework based on Datagrid Caches
- 3. Made scripts to automate simple deployments, side by side testing on production environment
- 4. Developed tool to automate the side by side testing with control on known discrepancies
- 5. Developed Event Listners to listen on CRUD events and make actions based on the events
- 6. Developed Restful services to publish the messages to kafka
- 7. Developed Rest Service to listen kafka messages and save them as POJO in Datagrid Cache
- 8. Developed Unit and IT Test Cases for the enterprise applications with JUnit, Jmeter
- 9. Developed an internal web based GUI tool with Angular JS, to receives data from REST API which retrieves data from Couchbase Database
- 10. Sanity testing suites on web services with SOAPUI/JMeter for REST/SOAP web services and comparison test on Unix Env
- 11. Scrum/Agile Methodology, Daily stand-up meetings, Weekly Planning Sessions, Monthly Retrospective meetings, Remote Work
- 12. Modified/developed the existing cache modules for a future enhancement or testing purpose

**Technologies:** Java/J2EE(7), Spring, Angular.JS, Shell/Bash, Oracle, Datagrid, Weblogic, Tableu, Postman, SOAP UI, JMeter, Junit, Jenkins, Maven, TFS, GCP, Kafka, Linux, Agile, Sonarqube

#### **HSENID BUSINESS SOLUTIONS, Sri Lanka**

#### **IMPLEMENTATION ENGINEER**

JULY 2015 - DECEMBER 2015

- 1. Implemented hSenid HRM system at client's sites including a product walk through to train employees' post-implementation to empower users to utilize system
- 2. Upgraded HRM Enterprise from V5 internal application to V8 at Client Side before the scheduled deadline
- 3. Designed and developed Crystal Reports based on customer requirements for HRM
- 4. Generated gueries on SQL and Oracle platforms according to the system requirements
- 5. Built solid relationships with clients to provide superior service
- 6. Conducted monthly progress meetings, delivered presentations to clients and steering committee & prepared meeting minuets

# RAMESH YOHA

- 7. Analyzed, troubleshot & assisted on server & application issues by remote connection
- 8. Spearheaded a data migration from old server to new server on SQL & Oracle Servers

Technologies: MS SQL, SQL Server 2008/2012, Crystal Reports, Oracle, VB .Net

#### AMRA PLASTIC MOULDERS, Ajax, ON, Canada

#### IT HELP DESK - MECHANICAL ENGINEER,

NOVEMBER 2013 - MAY 2014

- 1. Performed dual roles as both a mechanical engineer and IT help desk support
- 2. Set up, inspected, and troubleshot injection moulding machines & IT section Hardware
- 3. Utilized SolidWorks to design new drawings and modify existing drawings
- 4. Updated and maintained company website using WordPress
- 5. Measured parts with CMM to ensure proper fit & Created parts using various manufacturing machines
- 6. Relied upon by coworkers to make recommendations for new IT hardware purchases
- 7. Operated and trained on manufacturing software, Bespoke

Tools & Technologies: CMM, Crystal Reports, MS Office

#### FREELANCING, Canada/ Sri Lanka

#### FULL STACK DEVELOPER,

JULY 2014 - PRESENT

- Developed complete billing system with Javascript MERN stack (React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, Socket.io)
- 2. Designed & Developed Conceptual, logical and physical database design
- 3. Developed multiple CMS sites with Wordpress and Grav
- 4. Continuous Integration using Jenkins
- 5. Source Code Control using TFS, GitHub & GitLab
- 6. Cloud deployment to Google Cloud, Amazon AWS, Heroku.
- 7. Best practices using Agile, Sprint, Asana, and Slack

**Technologies:** Node.JS, React.JS, Express JS, Shell/Bash, Mongo DB, Postman, Jest, Socket.io, Jenkins, Docker, GCP, AWS, Heroku, Slack, GitHub/GitLab, Agile, Wordpress, Grav, Graphql, Sonarqube, Unix/Linux, Python, RESTFul Microservices, Asana

#### **EDUCATION & CREDENTIALS** -

# WEB & MOBILE APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT TRAINING NPOWER CANADA, TORONTO, CANADA PROFESSIONAL GRADUATE DIPLOMA (INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY) BRITISH COMPUTER SOCIETY, SRI LANKA BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (HONS) (MECHANICAL ENGINEERING) UNIVERSITY OF MORATUWA, SRI LANKA PROFESSIONAL GRADUATE DIPLOMA (INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY) 2011 - 2015 UNIVERSITY OF MORATUWA, SRI LANKA

#### **CERTIFICATIONS & PROJECTS** –

#### MICROSOFT TECHNOLOGY ASSOCIATE (MTA)

**JUNE 2016** 

#### ORACLE CERTIFIED ASSOCIATE - JAVA SE 8 PROGRAMMER 1

**JUNE 2015** 

#### **PUBLICATIONS:**

Y.Rameshkanna, R.B.A.Gayan, R.Ratheesan "Process optimization of Sri Lankan saucepan manufacturing industry by time study analysis" Research Publication, University of Moratuwa

#### PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIPS —

British Computer Society, Student Member, Sri Lanka	2011 - Present
Institute of Mechanical Engineering, Sri Lanka	2012 - Present
Institute of Engineering Sri Lanka, Student Member, Sri Lanka	2013 - 2015
Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineering, Sri Lanka	2011 - 2014